<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Requiem for GitHub&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:29:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-3825820</guid>
				<title>Re: It is happening</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-3825820</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 20:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>zoobab</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2946</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>When I was working with Pieter, we long discussed the strategy of trying to get rid of the founders. Strategy was clear: fire them, and recruit as many people as possible in order to inflate the value of the company. Github was largely run by 50 engineers, and I guess the investors wanted to inflate that number to increase the value, and sell to a big fish.</p> <p>I guess Pieter invites us to leave Github now.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-3823782</guid>
				<title>It is happening</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-3823782</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 07:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>upescatore</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>4192321</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi Pieter, I wish you were here to see that today it is happening. Wolves arrive to buy GitHub.</p> <p>As usual, with your intelligence you spotted that too!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2469308</guid>
				<title>Social Justice Warrior is a wrong word.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2469308</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 05:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Social Justice Warrior is a badge of honor for extremist feminists.<br /> The word confuses people. It is more appropriate to call them social control warriors. They are gestapo.</p> <p>By calling them social control warriors, people will perceive truth more accurately.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2455695</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2455695</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 22:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>yakshaving_jgt</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2534531</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <blockquote> <p>The court of public opinion is not a court, and street justice is not justice.</p> </blockquote> <p>Beautiful.</p> <p>Hear, hear, Hintjens.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2454881</guid>
				<title>Re: Psychopaths may not be the garbage collectors.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2454881</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 14:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Here is an interesting set of answers to this question: <a href="http://danieltenner.com/open-cultures/">http://danieltenner.com/open-cultures/</a></p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2453908</guid>
				<title>Psychopaths may not be the garbage collectors.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2453908</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 22:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <blockquote> <p>Psychopaths are the garbage collectors of human society.</p> </blockquote> <p>I started thinking that corporate psychopaths aren't the garbage collectors but parasitic necromancers that murder corporations and turn them into the undead to work little and earn a lot as executives. When a corporation is taken over by psychopaths, it becomes inefficient. In a free market, inefficient corporations should be garbage-collected quickly. I saw psychopaths circumvent garbage collection of free market by connecting to government programs and infecting virtually every company.</p> <p>In a hindsight, smart parasites should know that their hosts shouldn't die quick. They can animate the undead corporations for decades. And, it takes a century or more for massive undead corporations like microsoft and google to die.</p> <p>Silicon valley companies are an exception. Silicon valley VC investors learned to make money by liquidating companies as quick as possible.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2453545</guid>
				<title>GitHub didn&#039;t have to be sold if its equity structure was different.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:111/comments/show#post-2453545</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 10:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <blockquote> <p>when there is unguarded money on the table, the wolves arrive.</p> </blockquote> <p>Under a different equity model, GitHub could have been heavily guarded. GitHub could have been given a chance to fizzle out gracefully over decades or even centuries without being eaten by predators.</p> <p>The design of the organization could be set up such that no one has power to sell the company without agreements from all groups of the organization. I believe it's not difficult to engineer, in advance, a stalemate scenario for selling an organization.</p> <p>For example, if 50% or more of a company's equity is owned by another (possibly, non-profit and/or cooperative) entity that actually hires workers, selling the company requires the agreement of the other entity. The agreement cannot be derived by breaking the rules of the latter organization. I can engineer the latter organization so that nobody can sell the company without agreements from all groups in the organization.</p> <p>It's likely that GitHub's equity structure allowed a few people to sell the company to any predator. Trusting a few people not to sell the company is like leaving money on the table.</p> <blockquote> <p>we construct, and then when we reach a plateau, the wolves come along, destroy what we make, and liberate us to go forth and do better.</p> </blockquote> <p>I think there is disgrace in how GitHub was eaten alive by predators. It was not a difficult prey for venture capitals.</p> <p>Well guarded organizations have very good chances of defending themselves against wolves. I surmise even superhuman evil AIs cannot take over well-designed organizations directly with ease. Superhuman AIs will rather hack computers or launch DDoS attacks than buy or corrupt organizations.</p> <p>I'd like to design new corporate systems that fizzle out gracefully and give employees enough time to move without allowing predators to eat companies alive. I argue that there can be grace in garbage collection.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>