<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Patents Considered Evil&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:31:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1957344</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1957344</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 11:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>You miss the essential point that patents, and copyright, were designed to strip rights away from smaller creators who made their wealth from free trade. It is that simple. Laws and courts designed by powerful and wealthy men to control what others can do. When you claim the same protection, you are exhibiting Stockholm Syndrome.</p> <p>If you like, explain to me five ways you intend to protect your work through &quot;IP&quot; (the term is bogus since it covers many contradictory and often irrelevant laws, like plant variety rights, ship hull design rights, industrial designs, etc.), and I'll explain how to rob you, in each case, legally.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1957287</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1957287</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 09:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lalebarde</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1629498</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thanks for your deep replies Pieter. Now I get your point of view. For me, the most valuable thing one human being can do for his own lighting up is weilding his creativity. The consequence IMHO is that being able to perform it as a living shall be a premier right. So, I am far from your point of view.</p> <p>We are in a world of raptors. As a consequence, the small creator shall be protected. Copyright is not perfect, but comes with far less evil tricks than patents. No IP is not better than bad IP. Even for patents, you list a few examples you consider right.</p> <p>I agree sharing is also one of the most valuable thing one human being can do for his own lighting up. But every one shall be able to choose what he wants to share and what he wants to earn his living from. Otherwise, this is communism.</p> <p>Both do not oppose one each other. In my case, I contribute to 0MQ happily and fairly with a sharing attitude. But besides 0MQ, there is also a personal project I count on to earn my living. I have to publish my work if I want it to be adopted. Without IP, most IT actors that have some interest in it will just add it to their features unfairly. It is just non sense.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1956661</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1956661</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 20:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Copyright was always a protectionist legal concept designed to stop sharing. It was always for the booksellers and printers, not the authors.</p> <p>The insanity has become exposed as the price of copying has fallen.</p> <p>Only with hacks like GPL can copyright be made temporarily sane again. It should be abolished, and replaced with a right to copy, though not to claim someone else's identity (brand) and possibly attribution.</p> <p>Anyone should be able to copy this sentence. Only I should be allowed to claim I wrote it, and I am me.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1956108</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1956108</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 08:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lalebarde</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1629498</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <blockquote> <p>There is no &quot;fixing&quot; the patent system. This has been tried constantly for 150+ years.</p> </blockquote> <p>I consider humanity to be at its infancy, far from being mature with its only 6,000 years of known history. So 150 years is nothing. This is not a reason to not try something else.</p> <blockquote> <p>You cannot negotiate with sociopaths.</p> </blockquote> <p>That's the argument I totaly agree. That's why I titled my previous post &quot;<em>On a realistic point of view, I agree</em>&quot;.</p> <blockquote> <p>The theory that ideas can be &quot;owned&quot; is insane.</p> </blockquote> <p>I agree, but this is not the case in the french law, which enables only to patent <em>technical solutions to technical problems</em>. In addition, they shall prove to be innovative and usefull. As far as I know, the european law and the french one agree on that. This is far from being just <em>ideas</em>.</p> <blockquote> <p>Innovation comes from a free, fair, and competitive market.</p> </blockquote> <p>I agree.</p> <blockquote> <p>Anyone claiming that patents (like private copyright), in any form whatsoever, enable a free, fair, and competitive market, is working off delusion, or lies.</p> </blockquote> <p>That's not IMHO the driver:</p> <blockquote> <blockquote> <p>I deeply think anyone shall be able to publish his innovative work while keeping an economic advantage on it.</p> </blockquote> </blockquote> <p>Besides, we cannot argue on patents and copyrights together, it is so different. Do you think copyright is also bad and should be suppressed ?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1955095</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1955095</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 10:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>There is no &quot;fixing&quot; the patent system. This has been tried constantly for 150+ years. You cannot negotiate with sociopaths. They do not operate on that basis. Negotiation just means weakness. The only way to fix the patent system is to destroy it and remove all economic inventive to bring lawyers into the process of innovation.</p> <p>The theory that ideas can be &quot;owned&quot; is insane. The theory that this creates more innovation is insane. The theory that without private monopolies, people will stop innovating is insane. The theory that private monopolies help smaller innovators is insane.</p> <p>Innovation comes from a free, fair, and competitive market. No more, no less. Anyone claiming that patents (like private copyright), in any form whatsoever, enable a free, fair, and competitive market, is working off delusion, or lies.</p> <p>I expand on this in more detail in Culture &amp; Empire.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1953654</guid>
				<title>On a realistic point of view, I agree, but...</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:31/comments/show#post-1953654</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 10:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lalebarde</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1629498</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>You refer to the french patent law and reproach it to enable to patent ideas. This is not the case. The french patent law is the most demanding one, it enables only to patent technical solutions to technical problems.</p> <p>Anyway, I mostly agree with the rest of your arguments: the patent ecosystem is parasited by its officers, plus the lawyers, raptors that produce nothing, and unfair corporates.</p> <p>But I don't conclude as you do that suppressing patents is the solution. I deeply think anyone shall be able to publish his innovative work while keeping an economic advantage on it. Suppressing patents as they are defined today, yes, but not for nothing. Still, designing a new system that would be fair and robust against parasites looks not easy.</p> <p>It is true that ideas are in the air and raise independently in several places in the same time. But them, it would be fair that all legitimate inventor gain an economical advantage, not only the first one who claims. On the other side, letting others just copy without effort is unfair. But probably it would be too complex to make this happen because it would require research track records for proofs and then lawyers, officers, and the same kind of system that has proved already to be bad with patents.</p> <p>Shall we conclude there is no solution ?</p> <p>I think we should try at least the following:</p> <ol> <li>Fair arbitration of multiple inventors when evidence can be provided before the work is published. Each one shall be able to produce and sell in conformity with his invention even if they recover one each other.</li> <li>Suppress any right to software patent owners who produce nothing. I call here &quot;software patent&quot; any patent on any technology that can be sold or exchanged as a software program only (this includes for example algorithms). I restrict this to software as other inventions require often big invests. This implies that the software inventor has developped a prototype to be quite market ready before registering his patent.</li> <li>Suppress any right to not-software patent owners who produce nothing in a reasonable time depending on the technology. At least evidence of production investments shall be available.</li> <li>For small and medium companies, each country shall take over their defense, independently of the agencies that deliver the patents. This would have the positive effect to avoid unlegitimate patents.</li> </ol> <p>Ok, this would be very hard to make this happen due to lobbies and the complexity of international commerce and legal systems. It is obviously not perfect, plus it is a draft, and it will always enable raptors to use workaround tricks. But we are looking for the less bad solution, isn't it ?</p> <p>Anyway, what do you think of that ?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>