<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Confessions of a Necromancer&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:28:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-3799357</guid>
				<title>herpes cure for various virus</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-3799357</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 23:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Chrisline</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>4058897</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hello everyone am here to share my testimony. I was suffering from BREAST CANCER for the past 3 years and my Dr told me that there is nothing he could do, after the 5 times chemotherapy and radiation and i was not responding to treatment and not even getting better and i had no money for Surgery because it was too expensive for me. I was frustrated and confused, seeking advice from people until a friend told me about Dr. Osebulu Herbal Medicine and herbal cannabis oil and its fast curing ability of any kind of cancer and told me that her mother's LUNGS CANCER was cured by the same Doctor Osebulu. I was desperate to to have the HERBS and i contacted Dr. Osebulu via email to get the miraculous oil. The Dr send me the Herbal Medicine and Cannabis oil through FedEx, to cut the long story short, i got Completely Cured after taking the Herbs for a week. To cut the long story short, as i am writing this testimony on this Blog am so strong and healthy no more cancer in my body again. I did my test and the Doctor confirmed it, i do not have BREAST CANCER anymore which he (The Medical Doctor) was Shock when he confirmed it. I really want to Appreciate Dr Osebulu who got me cured with the help of his herbal medicine and to God Be All The Glory.</p> <p>He also have a herbal cure for the Following DISEASES and INFECTIONS below, this is 100% Real.</p> <p>-GENITAL WARTS<br /> -GENITAL AND ORAL HERPES<br /> -HIV<br /> -DIABETES<br /> -PENIS ENLARGEMENT AND WEAK ERECTION<br /> -VIRGINA PROBLEM<br /> -WHOOPING COUGH<br /> -STROKE<br /> -PILE<br /> -LOW SPERM COUNT<br /> -ASTHMA<br /> -FIBROID<br /> -TOOTH PAIN<br /> -BARENESS/INFERTILITY<br /> -DIARRHEA and so on&#8230;</p> <p>EMAIL: <span class="wiki-email">moc.liamtoh|emohllepsulubesord#moc.liamtoh|emohllepsulubesord</span></p> <p>Call/WhatsApp Dr. Osebulu Now: +2348083221034</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-3566772</guid>
				<title>Spam</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-3566772</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 03:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Sean Crosby</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>3282840</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hey, so uh, I'm trying to hook this email up with some spam to try and replicate what James Veitch has done, so uh&#8230; if anyone here could send me some spam (I especially like those 'Nigerian Prince' scams) my email is seancrosby12345 and it's a gmail account. Unfortunately I can't actually add the ending part, because I'm a low level user, and can't add any links.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2829111</guid>
				<title>service ac bsd</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2829111</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 14:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>serviceacbsd</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>3139749</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>awesome adventure&#8230;</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2665873</guid>
				<title>an awesome read</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2665873</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Rares Dumitrescu</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2850983</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>took me a while to read this article but it's been like reading an adventure book. thanks.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2665387</guid>
				<title>Thanks indeed</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2665387</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 19:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>hwb</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2850117</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Just today I was in a meeting in a German administrative office regarding the integration of many different systems in the GIS subculture. It's much like you described in that one project at the cement factory with different parties involved. Over the past few years I also managed to get people which were previously a little hostile (not really hostile, but not cooperative either) to be in our boat to get things done. This article just got me thinking, perhaps my stance of being just a good coder may have to change over time, and I'll finally have to master people skills&#8230;</p> <p>Then I read about your demise (I hope Internet access is good in heaven), and can just thank you for this beautiful writeup regarding 'Enterprise' software work to get Things Done. I'm a few decades younger, but I can absolutely relate to you. I've made most of the mistakes you made (caring too much about technology and not realizing 'getting rich quick' opportunities), but IMHO it's just the way we are. Kudos! And a good afterlife!</p> <p>If anyone related/knowing this man reads this, all I can say is that this article (the 'probably my last article' article also moved me) is one that is for me so obviously honest, I find it is one of the best. That he found the time to write this up is really touching me and I think many others!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2665350</guid>
				<title>We&#039;ll miss you</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2665350</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 17:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lsvalgaard</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2839966</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Leif &amp; Vera</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2664977</guid>
				<title>Thanks a lot</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2664977</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 21:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>niederstadt</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>482362</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>It took me all weekend to read this and I want to say thank you for sharing your experiences.<br /> And I want to ask your permission to use one sentence from your post as my new forum signature - as a tribute to you and your writings.</p> <p>Thanks again!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2663964</guid>
				<title>Wonderful</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2663964</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>greggirwin</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>583361</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thanks for continuing to write for us Pieter. You'll be happy or horrified to know that Xitami is still running in production. One of my favorite pieces of software ever. And while I've never had to invoke your name in an appeal to authority, I always knew you were out there whenever I wrote a code generator.</p> <p>And I'll take a quiet walk down memory lane myself, about past code and people, and life's lessons learned.</p> <p>Warmest regards, always.</p> <p>P.S. Where you say &quot;We were able to increase performance from 150K messages/second to 600 messages/second.&quot;, the numbers seem askew. A missing K perhaps?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2660964</guid>
				<title>Thank you.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2660964</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 14:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>jonsg</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2844001</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you, from all the bright-eyed naifs never expecting the crush of corporate politics.<br /> Thank you, from all the huddled masses toiling in the cubicle farms.<br /> Thank you, from the war-grizzled veterans, nodding at every shared experience.</p> <p>This was a seminal piece, and I hope it gets shared to all heck.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2660710</guid>
				<title>Fascinating</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2660710</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 01:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>ToJaSlawek</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2843575</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2660326</guid>
				<title>Amazing Story</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2660326</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 06:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>gtds</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2843059</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Can't believe I've been two decades in the industry and was hitherto unaware of your work (I sort of vaguely knew your name). Anyway, there's not much I can say that that does it justice, but it was truly an inspirational and riveting memoir whose lessons I will carry with me and hopefully put to some use! Thank you.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2659871</guid>
				<title>Some great lessons in life!</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2659871</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>jtdavies</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2768050</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi Pieter, lots of interesting memories there, there was a lot on your side I wasn't aware of, particularly with your family at the time, my condolences.</p> <p>As someone who was there at the time (as you know in JPMC and working with &quot;John&quot;) I can corroborate everything you said. I would however say, in John's defence, that he never said anything bad about you and always respected and spoke highly of you in private. When I first saw the spec (and met you) it was very clearly yours, John had the vision and the position at the bank to make it happen. You very clearly implemented that vision, not just the spec but the first and only version JPMC ever used.<br /> Putting AMQP aside you point out a lot of life lessons, some I've learnt in similar ways, some I'm struggling with now, hearing them from you will help me navigate though the crap.<br /> It was great spending an evening with you drinking beer about a year ago, if you're still allowed to drink have one from me and thanks for writing this.</p> <p>-John-</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2655706</guid>
				<title>Re: MS-DOS Monitor</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2655706</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lsvalgaard</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2839966</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>As a low-karma guest I had to replace &quot;\&quot; with &quot;-&quot;</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2655700</guid>
				<title>MS-DOS Monitor</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2655700</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lsvalgaard</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2839966</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Ah, remembering the MS-DOS Monitor. I fired up a 25-year old laptop [yes, we had those back then and it [an Everett] still runs] and pulled [via an intermediate machine that could read floppies] the code for the Monitor. For your enjoyment, I put it on my website:<br /> www.leif.org-research-MONITOR.pdf</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2654676</guid>
				<title>very interesting and at times instructive essay</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2654676</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 19:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Sergei Sergejev</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2837357</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I've spent three evenings reading this (<em>only to find now that essay was quite updated. Must re-read!</em>) and enjoyed every moment. Felt sorry for your family for 2005 tragedy and being occupied by work at that time, laughed out loud in the room at the project finished under budget and became a bit sad at shitty people story. Those are some familiar and right lessons there. I'm hooked to read your books now (and sad there won't be any new :'( )</p> <p>I'm only 9 years in IT and learned the issue of politics, liars and social climbers the hard way and early in my career. I actually like the fact I learned it soon. I'm currently recovering from yet another toxic environment, struggling with insomnia, anxiety (, depression?) and fatigue.</p> <p>I'll quote this part in my (possible) future presentations:</p> <blockquote> <p>&quot;It doesn't matter how good the design, when there are unresolved problems in the organization.</p> <p>And so gradually I shifted from technical architect to social architect. From caring about technical designs to caring about people and the psychology that drives them. Because in the end, this is what seems to make the difference between a working project and a failure&quot;</p> </blockquote> <p>Same said by Jerry Weinberg - &quot;No matter how it looks at first, it's always a people problem&quot;. Same learned from Jim Coplien, my blue pill scrum teacher and the organizational patterns guy, a lot Scrum's rules come from different failure and success stories. The team sizes, the relative estimation, standups etc. Then there's negotiation techniques. The latter seem quite important, especially given that a lot of us geeks are closed and humble people. I recently tweeted that I'd take away computers from first semester Computer Science students and would teach them how to talk, clarify and argue with people, only then learn to code. We probably would be so much better off!</p> <p>I wanted to become a doctor in high school, but became as I see it a software and software projects doctor. I think I'll continue this way (until I get a stroke or heart attack (or have enough money to retire early and start writing books)), because it seems there are not so many people in teams who see dysfunctions, have the guts to name them and to propose ideas. Someone has to do it, but needs to indeed set limits and not burn ones self.</p> <p>Thank you, it was a influential read!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2654079</guid>
				<title>A good read!</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2654079</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 16:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Jonathan Schultz</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>11839</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Glad to have been the C64 pirate (anyone remember Sadistic Software?) and your collaborator at the ICFTU, GSL, STEP and AMQP.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2648254</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2648254</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 13:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Best years of my professional life, working with you. :-)</p> <p>Remember the time we went for lunch to the pizza place and ordered a *huge* pizza for two, and a bottle of red wine, and when we'd finished it, we kind of paused for a second, both turned to the waiter and said, &quot;same again please!&quot;</p> <p>And the time you got annoyed on a Friday that Microsoft needed 16MB for OS/2 &quot;because multitasking&quot; so you came back on Monday with a working MS-DOS multitasker in ~1,000 assembler instructions.</p> <p>Good times, and thanks for them.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2647820</guid>
				<title>Blinking lights</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2647820</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>zoobab</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2946</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>&quot;seeing a light turn on, and turn off again.&quot;</p> <p>echo 1 &gt; /sys/class/gpio1/value<br /> echo 0 &gt; /sys/class/gpio1/value</p> <p>Glard!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2645564</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:125/comments/show#post-2645564</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 04:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lsvalgaard</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2839966</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Pieter, rather than complaining, I want to tell you that I enjoyed working with you. We learned a lot, about machines, code, and [especially and most importantly] people.<br /> Leif.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>