<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Fighting Cancer&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:28:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2631384</guid>
				<title>Best regards to a kindred spirit</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2631384</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Ryan Patridge</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2838166</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Very well written, your words resonate strongly with me. I was diagnosed with AML two years ago (a variety with a poor prognosis). Underwent chemo, radiation, and a bone marrow transplant, am still recovering and in remission, for now. I've spent a decent amount of time considering cancer, mortality, death positivity, and such matters. I came to many of the same conclusions and perspectives as you, but you've put them into language much better than any of my attempts. It bolsters my spirit and simultaneously gives me an excellent narrative I can easily share with others, if they seek to better understand my own story. Thank you very much for all your contributions while cohabitating this reality. I hope your death is as triumphantly positive as your life.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2626630</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2626630</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 22:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Sergei Sergejev</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2837357</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Pieter, it's very good that you keep this blog and raise these topics. I know for sure that you are not alone in these thoughts and that the situation around such diseases will improve as people speak about it more open like you do.</p> <p>Strength to you and your family!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2578764</guid>
				<title>Taming cancer (continued)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2578764</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 14:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Rahul Choudhary</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2822103</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>i can help, maybe. need some disease history and daily dietary intake.</p> <p>from across the posts, could make out an operation 5yrs ago, liver related. something came up again a yr ago or so. esophagus cramps month or so ago. now, something's not ok in the right lung. what's nasty growing where? any intercontinental trip before the last resurgence?</p> <p>lots of water intake is hard? ~12qt/day, &lt;1.5qt/hr is the maximum for extremely fit humans. staying over hydrated is always better</p> <p>hot water bottle heat therapy any help?</p> <p>0.5qt yogurt daily is doable?</p> <p>lots of thin hot veggie soup is doable?</p> <p>how does a bowl of cilantro taste? like blended with green chili, some salt</p> <p>any roughness in the upper pharynx while breathing, upper common section for air/food until the epiglottis?</p> <p>had a benign lymphoma type thing at 4, painful; a dear aunt (RIP, Canadian doc) succumbed to pancreatic couple years back; a village cousin survived tracheal few years back. read a fair bit, who knows how much is enough. not a doc, keen interest otw, bio was always a lot easier in high school than phy/chem/math. just in case, rahulchoudhary at me dot com</p> <p>best wishes to you and your family in these trying times, Rahul</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2576455</guid>
				<title>Thanks for sharing</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2576455</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 16:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Nicolas Leclercq</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1479357</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Your article is deeply changing the way we see life-threatening illness. Most of us are mute and frozen facing such a situation. We now have a better idea of what is the best way to behave in order to really help. We are also better prepared in case it's our turn to face illness.</p> <p>You're doing your best to slowly cross the tunnel with peace and dignity. Life can't have no meaning and you could discover another world at the other end - a world making use of radically different protocols&#8230;</p> <p>Thanks for all Pieter.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2576368</guid>
				<title>Taming cancer</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2576368</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 12:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Rahul Choudhary</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2822103</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>my old man told me 'you don't know pain is' last winter. Every breath was a torture, pain radiating out to the heart from the lower left lung. 4days of splatoons and he recovered, a burst blood vessel that healed i think. You do too, heal quicker, naturebless</p> <p>what does doc say about Dr. Issels? issels.com; inspired by his thoughts, generally healthy me spent a summer in a semi desert with a fan. heat is good, bad things die quicker. docs call it hyperthermia. their personalized techniques solve for a few dozen types of this nasty thing. all the best, Rahul</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2572107</guid>
				<title>Thank you for sharing</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2572107</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 15:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>codesurgeon</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2819636</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you for sharing your experiences and insights, Pieter. No matter how much any- and everyone would like to put off thinking about matters of terminal disease, it'll be an issue for all of us in some form or another at some point in our lives.<br /> Having your thoughts and posts to think of, will help.</p> <p>Thank you and all the best to you and your family &#8230; and thank you for all your previous tech writing ;)</p> <p>&#8212; Mustafa</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2571167</guid>
				<title>With Great Appreciation</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2571167</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 19:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>FlyingAvatar</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2818954</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Your posts over the past months have given me an important perspective on illness and death that I will carry to my own, and I suspect will help me with others that I am likely to face.</p> <p>Thank you for this and your courage to analyze and share about a scenario that many find strangely taboo.</p> <p>Kind regards,</p> <p>-Andy</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2571114</guid>
				<title>Keep fighing...</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2571114</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 18:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Craiggers</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2818913</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Not the cancer mind you&#8230; you're doing great at handling that. Fighting the awful conversation around cancer. The cruelty people say unbeknownst to themselves to others suffering. In volunteering with Hospice I cannot stress enough the crazy things people say/do when their loved ones are dying. Most often it comes from a good place but it can difficult to navigate.</p> <p>I think if we as a society learned to talk through problems in much more things than in death we'd stand to gain a lot of ground as a society. It's easy for to say that right now at least as my problems nothing compared to most but in thinking about how everyone experiences death why is it so hard for all of us to talk more to each other.</p> <p>Asynchronous Human Messaging needs to improve :)</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2571004</guid>
				<title>quality of life with chemo</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2571004</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 15:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>mxvanzant</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2720576</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Pieter,</p> <p>There is much evidence for reduced pain, better appetite, and improved outcomes with high dose vitamin C therapy in conjunction with chemo.</p> <p>You can look at doctoryourself com and also the Journal of Orthomolecular Medicine's web site.</p> <p>Hope this helps you feel better.</p> <p>And thanks for ZeroMQ!</p> <p>Mike</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2568565</guid>
				<title>Thank you, Pieter</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2568565</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 14:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Ankush Thakur</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2817418</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Pieter, I discovered ZeroMQ a few days ago, and imagine my surprise at reading this! Well, like you write, there are no easy conversations about death. I wish you'd stick around for much longer, but for now &quot;thank you&quot; is all I can say.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2566481</guid>
				<title>Thank you so much</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2566481</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 20:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>rocksportrocker</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2816094</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Dear Peter,</p> <p>first I have to say that I missed the oportunity to participate in a zeromq workshop on a Europython conference and regret this since then, now even more, day by day.</p> <p>I have to say that I nearly &quot;dyed&quot; 20 years ago, not physically but I suffered from severe psychic illnes with a wrong diagnosis and wrong medical treatment. Although my body was functioning, the medication supressed my mind and soul so much that I was a walking zombie, not able to think, not able to feel, not able to reflect. Luckily the wrong treatment was recognized after 10 years and the implications brought me back to live, much more than I ever could imagine at this time.</p> <p>I still have the feeling of having a second chance to live and I'm thankful for this day by day. Since them I'm thinking about death, not daily, not in a depressed way or with fear. Still I can not fade out that death will happen, sooner or later. Still my thoughts are neutral and analytic. And I still ask myself if I can maintain my attitude or if I fool myself somehow in regard of this &quot;unthinkable event&quot;.</p> <p>Reading your thoughts supports me to be on the right track and I regard your writings as infinitely valuable for me, and I'm very sure for many others.</p> <p>So even if you don't know me, be sure that I'll remind you and your efforts every time I type &quot;import zmq&quot;. Please go on with sharing your thoughts. I wish you all the best.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2566480</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2566480</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 20:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Gabrys</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2462</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you for writing this. As humanity fought almost all other diseases it seems inevitable most of us will die in car accidents or from cancer. This gives me a rough idea how most of us end. I think you approach your situation in a very good way. I love the fact you managed to go camping (well, sort of).</p> <p>Feel good!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2566342</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:123/comments/show#post-2566342</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 15:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fran Macilvey</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2719503</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you for including us in your daily activities, with your writing, and so clearly explaining what is happening. I can see it in my mind's eye as you describe, which is wonderful. Thoughtful of you.</p> <p>Thank you also for saying that we are together. I like to think so, even if I'm lying at night awake and thinking of you. My thoughts come to you, all the time and there is never a time when I am not thinking of you all, and wishing you well. :)</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>