<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Five Years, Five Wishes&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:29:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2431801</guid>
				<title>No Regrets</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2431801</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Pieter m Smit</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2418705</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>hi Pieter,</p> <p>Thanks for sharing.</p> <p>I was diagnosed with Stage 3 Testicular Cancer in December 2009. Strange how a long uncertain recovery forces you to re-evaluate your live choices&#8230;</p> <p>I greatly admire all your accomplishments. My focus was mostly personal afterwards. With the kids getting older now, I hope to be part of changing the world for the better :).</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2422384</guid>
				<title>Re: I have a few comments and questions.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2422384</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 00:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>The meaning of institution is broader than you currently think.</p> <p>According to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Institution">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Institution</a>, Institutions are &quot;stable, valued, recurring patterns of behavior.&quot; As structures or mechanisms of social order, they govern the behaviour of a set of individuals within a given community. Institutions are identified with a social purpose, transcending individuals and intentions by mediating the rules that govern living behavior. The term &quot;institution&quot; commonly applies to a custom or behavior pattern important to a society, and to particular formal organizations of the government and public services. As structures and mechanisms of social order, institutions are a principal object of study in social sciences such as political science, anthropology, economics, and sociology</p> <p>In case of ZeroMQ community, it is governed by C4.1 and a benevolent dictator who enforces it. C4.1 is an attempt to repeat a desired pattern of behaviors. An institution doesn't need to have designated officers, offices, and/or managers.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2422150</guid>
				<title>Re: I have a few comments and questions.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2422150</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>If you design organizations, understand how the ZeroMQ community works. It's not an institution. It's a market of projects, each independent and many competing, who share knowledge and trade expertise. The market regulates itself with contracts that are carefully designed to make it unprofitable for bad actors to interfere.</p> <p>No structure, no organization. I'm dead serious: there is no ZeroMQ Foundation, no staff, no offices. This isn't laziness, it's by design.</p> <p>I've built structure and organization often and know how much it consumes.</p> <p>The smartphone: well, it let me check my own symptoms rapidly and exclude the possible candidates. I was turning yellow. The choices were: gall stones, or tumor in my bile duct. The ultrasound showed no stones, one hour after I was admitted. It took them one week more to do a biopsy.</p> <p>As for not getting cancer&#8230; the probable cause in my case was a parasite called a liver fluke, which attaches to the bile duct and produces carcinogens. Nature is nice like that. The parasite comes from farmed fresh-water fish. The cancer I had is a major cause of death in SE Asia. I think it was cheap sushi that almost killed me.</p> <p>And lastly, to garbage collection. It's not pejorative. Life is append only. We make space for others, that is how it works and has to work.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2421341</guid>
				<title>I have a few comments and questions.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:109/comments/show#post-2421341</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>1) &quot;We all die eventually, which is a good thing. Death is the Great Garbage Collector. Yet we go through extraordinary effort to not die, yet.&quot;</p> <p>Congratulations for surviving a fast-growing cancer.<br /> Perhaps, it's harsh to a survivor to say that I do not like to consider myself as a garbage to be collected. I and you are not garbages. There should be other ways than dying of cancer to make humans behave( or collect garbages to speak metaphorically). We deserve to treat ourselves better after everything you and I have done and will do to make the world a better place.</p> <p>2) The only long-term cure for cancer is life extension therapies.</p> <p>According to Aubrey de Grey(Watch www.youtube.com watch?v=pPqGrKg_HqA for introduction to his research), aging process increases the probability of getting cancer and various diseases related to old age. It means if you live long enough, you're going to be afflicted with any one of cancer, heart disease, and various other diseases. Curing the symptomps of diseases only delays the inevitable for a while. The only long-term cure to diseases of old age is to keep your body healthy with life extension therapies. So, life extension research is actually about maintaining optimal health no matter how old you are. David Sinclair could release the first life extension drug or therapy within a decade. Just, hang on for some decades. Technological growth is or can be exponential. You may be able to hope for seeing your grand grand children. I like to give people hope.</p> <p>3) &quot;There are good institutions, such as the medical system that saved my life.&quot;</p> <p>The medical institution is significantly better than the mainstream business. However, in my opinion, it is not good enough, and we can design a much better institution than that.</p> <p>By the way, how did your smartphone diagnose you faster and more accurately than doctors? I want to know.</p> <p>4) &quot;The more we invest in structure and organization, the stupider we become.&quot;</p> <p>Not necessarily. You invested a lot of time into community building, and you arrived at a good institution such as zeromq community. Zeromq community is a community institution in the same way as LaTeX user groups(www.tug.org) are. Just because institutions of the past are cruel and stupid, it doesn't mean newly designed institutions are and will be bad. People learn from mistakes of the past and design better things.</p> <p>We just have to design better institutions that outcompete the mainstream business financially and provide technologists with opportunities to manage their own affairs where they are not dominated by typical corporate managers.</p> <p>5) I'm designing a cooperative institution for long-term technological challenges.</p> <p>The banks do not fund businesses whose success rates are under 90%, and they shouldn't take more risk than they do now. The mainstream business is focused on short-term gains, so it doesn't fund long-term technical challenges. Venture capitals in silicon valley mostly fund companies that go viral within 3-4 years or die. Other places do not have as much money as silicon valley, yet.</p> <p>Giant companies like facebook, google, and microsoft hire a few researchers, but that's not good enough. Meanwhile, millions of talented people on this planet are not given financial opportunities to contribute by technical research like rich hickey's work on clojure.</p> <p>The initial idea for a new institution came from the history of polycentric legal system, co-operatives, and michaelochurch.wordpress.com slash 2015 slash 10 slash 01 slash silicon-valley-can-be-beaten</p> <p>I started designing a new institution a few days ago. I'll soon read psychopath code and some other books for more information.</p> <p>I will contact you for advice on how to minimize or even eradicate vulnerabilities to trolls and psychopaths in the kind of institution I'm designing. I can't do this alone.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>