<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;The Cretan Method&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:30:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2407163</guid>
				<title>Identity</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2407163</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 18:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Nikkia</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2339964</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thanks for your essay! This was a great read. :)</p> <p>The identity section made me curious about the need to protect identity, especially in the real life. Trying to maintain multiple identities seems to be generally frowned upon; I think it may be perceived to be unhealthy. Is it really? How unrecognizable should one expect to be, until that ceases to be a need for privacy and begins to be a problem? What theories confirm that a better control of what and when is disclosed not only feels good to us now, but that attaching a badge to everybody would harm us? With technology advancements, permanent, public identity could leak from cyberspace to real life and become an inescapable reality.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2209187</guid>
				<title>Re: Let&#039;s falsify the gender part</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2209187</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 22:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Good points. I'm glad to have provoked you to think about these stories.</p> <p><a href="http://www.human.cornell.edu/hd/ciws/upload/SexDifferencesMathIntensiveFields.pdf">This study</a> suggests that women enter STEM fields ahead of men, and drop off due to &quot;fertility choices&quot;. This doesn't explain how women are well represented in other areas though.</p> <p>As for women making better scientists, <a href="http://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2014/04/girls-grades.aspx">many studies</a> show that girls outperform boys up until they enter university or college. Science as well as maths, and languages.</p> <p>As for IQ tests, they are easily falsified. Simply practicing for a few days will raise your measured score significantly. I've done that.</p> <p>Why do young men enjoy magical doctrine? Why are formal religious organizations, political movements, and middle management stuffed with &quot;almost employed&quot; men and a minority of women? The suspension of disbelief is part of a typically male mindset that succumbs to authority, to group think, and to ideology.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2209120</guid>
				<title>Let&#039;s falsify the gender part</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2209120</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 20:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>graffic</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2046120</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I'm going to share my theories and try to falsify what you said about the gender issues. It would be great if you try to falsify mine too, having some kind of dialogue helps.</p> <p><strong>“men don’t have anything to do”</strong><br /> Women are the majority of students in universities. In average the minority is men. The only studies where women are minorities are STEM.</p> <p>If higher education is an issue of not having anything better to do, women seem to have nothing better to do (using your logic).</p> <p><strong>“The observation that women make better scientists than men is not new.”</strong><br /> Does it even exist? Statistics say that men, at the brilliant IQ level, outnumber women 8 to one. The average IQ also favours men.</p> <p>It is true that you’re talking about scientists and I’m talking about IQ. You can check math scores and find more men on the right tail of the distribution.</p> <p>Are these scores what you need to be a good scientist? I’m sure they’re just a part. Although it correlates with the gender gap in STEM.</p> <p><strong>“most young women are too busy building real social networks to dedicate years of their lives to the study of nonsense.”</strong><br /> So STEM is nonsense. What happens with the other studies where men are minorities? Are they nonsense too?</p> <p>Since they’re high education studies, by default any degree, not only STEM should be nonsense. But since more women an in university than men. It seems that mostly young women are dedicating years to study nonsense.</p> <p><strong>“not-quite employed man”</strong></p> <p>What is that?</p> <p><strong>“Magical theories are as attractive to young men as they are distasteful to young women”</strong><br /> Why not the opposite? Aren’t science fields the home of the scientific method? Why women don’t feel attracted to the scientific method and find themselves in other degrees far away from it?</p> <p>Show me the code. Code wins any discussion. Red, green, refactor. Leave the code in a better state for the next coworker. Why are you putting your focus in popularity pageant votes? You paint the situation like there is no scientific process at all.</p> <p><strong>Closing thoughts</strong><br /> Great article.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2197573</guid>
				<title>You are so wrong that I would like to show you how much.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2197573</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 13:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Dabus</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2040027</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>We are not quite yet here, but coming :-)</p> <p>What you share is so inspiring that we actually use it&#8230;</p> <p>Thx.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2175857</guid>
				<title>Cretan as from Crete? I guess not.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:81/comments/show#post-2175857</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 02:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Apostolis Xekoukoul</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1959035</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Just letting you note that there is a beautiful island called Crete and we are called Cretan.</p> <p>Apart from that, I really like your theories. If I remember correctly, you have a physics degree and that shows in your methodology.</p> <p>I am one those people who think that their theory is always wrong and always try to improve it but this is considered a weakness from the point of view of the fairy tale theorists.</p> <p>Because we leave in a world where the fairy tales are not written by fiction writers but by politicians, and thus we have a centralized control of the fiction, it is important to decentralize the creation process of the myth to as many people as possible.</p> <p>I do believe that interpersonal trust is the only way for people to valuate theories which they cannot prove themselves. Thus we need a formal trust network that filters/transmits information to others.</p> <p>If previously the information reached the user in one hop, we need to use the network to transmit with multiple trusted hops. Here we need to check for a specific problem:</p> <p>Multiple hops affect the quality of the information received but at the same time multiple hops allow for strong trust links.</p> <p>Strong trust links also allow for feedback to traverse back and change the trust network if not listened to.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>