<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Ten Steps to Better Public Speaking&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:29:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2503390</guid>
				<title>Re: never raising your hands?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2503390</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 09:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Body language is a delicate thing. Try standing in front of someone, then raise your hand to body height. Then raise it above head height. Then ask the person if they felt differently each time. Most people will interpret the high raised hand as aggressive, threatening. That is powerful body language when you are provoking a mob. When speaking to friends in a group, it invokes all the wrong emotions.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2503385</guid>
				<title>never raising your hands?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2503385</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 09:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Jeroen De Dauw</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2733484</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Can someone elaborate (or link to information on) &quot;never raising your hands above your shoulders&quot;? I'd like to know why this is bad, and how bad different gestures of this type are.</p> <p>Thanks so much for this post. I've wanted good information on how to improve my speaking skills for some time, and this is exactly what I needed.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2464367</guid>
				<title>Re: No slides, post talks?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2464367</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I wrote that assuming most people won't ditch slides. Otherwise, I sometimes like to write my talks as articles before/after the event.</p> <p>Pictures can of course help a lot. I'm hoping eventually to have a live drawing approach which works with a tablet in my hand.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2464318</guid>
				<title>No slides, post talks?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2464318</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 16:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>jeff_abrahamson</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2563835</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>&quot;Once you drink the github koolaid, you can use it for everything. Put your talks there, and accept pull requests.&quot;</p> <p>Good post, thanks. But, er, what do you put online with no slides? (I see you post your videos, but pull requests to videos surely isn't what you mean.)</p> <p>There's a tricky middle ground, where I'm talking about something that could benefit (quite a lot) from a picture. Imagine I'm explaining Newton's method, and showing a few pictures of stepping through the algorithm on a curve makes it all easier to understand.</p> <p>But for much of the talk, I don't need slides. And then I have this projector going. I can put up blank slides. Often I put up a slide with just one or two words that summarize what I'm talking about now.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2417946</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2417946</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 12:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Jan Bols</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2359839</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <blockquote> <p>When you use slides, the audience watches the screen, not you.</p> </blockquote> <p>This is also true when streams of tweets are being projected on big screens left and right of the speaker.</p> <p>To all conference organizers: <em>twitter is a wonderful thing, but please, keep it out of the room where the talk is held</em>. It's so difficult to keep focused on what Melvin Conway is trying to present when everyone's opinions are constantly being projected ;-)</p> <p>Greetings<br /> Jan</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2417853</guid>
				<title>Re: waterfall talks</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2417853</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 08:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Yes, this is a great process&#8230;</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2417847</guid>
				<title>waterfall talks</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:107/comments/show#post-2417847</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 07:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Mathias Verraes</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2359648</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Great stuff. My heuristic for choosing what to talk about is: Have I explained this to people before? When I've tried to give talks that I wrote in isolation, I've had terrible results. But if it's a topic that I find myself explaining over and over again, at my clients or in social settings, it means I have direct one-on-one experience with how people react, what kind of questions they ask, which analogies work or not.</p> <p>The next step is finding a small free meetup, where I do a half-improvised talk using a whiteboard. (No slides, after you advised me to do without two years ago.) Typically they are long and messy. I start with a joke about the audience being guinea pigs, or that they'll get the 0 euro back they paid to attend. The final step is turning them into proper 45m talks. I do still use slides there, because I tend to talk about visualising software models, and whiteboards are unpractical with large audiences.</p> <p>What I'm saying is, a big bang presentation is risky. Many people write their presentation and then test it on some colleagues, but that is still a waterfall method. You're already forced into a structure. First do the talk, then (if you must) write the talk.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>