<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;Why I&#039;ve Quit Twitter&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:29:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2495871</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2495871</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 09:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fran Macilvey</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2719503</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you for outing Hate in its many guises.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2490382</guid>
				<title>Re: Great article</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2490382</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thanks for your comment, it's interesting to get the perspective. We do use 'race' as a shorthand in so many different situations. Here in Brussels we use 'religion' instead, and it's as troublesome.</p> <p>It's sure that we have large extended families who fight over territory and power, and many societies are defined by these conflicts&#8230; and the answer always seems to be to find common interests and profits, and allow the borders to dissolve over time. It can take a long time. Perhaps this is why I find the divisionist rhetoric so abhorrent, because it seeks to push us in the opposite direction.</p> <p>I avoided using the term &quot;regressive left&quot; because I wanted to pull apart the two strands of 3WF and BLC. Perhaps in the UK where left wing politics are more real, there is a real regressive left movement.</p> <p>I can't honestly even see a regressive left in the US, just different cults who have some shared language and common &quot;enemies&quot;.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2490350</guid>
				<title>Great article</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2490350</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 11:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>benforeva</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2690837</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thanks for writing this and I mostly agree with you. I have never equated 3WF with a hatred of femaleness but it makes a lot of sense when I consider it. I have a few female friends who reject feminism, I now wonder if they do so because they have been able to identify this hatred.</p> <p>I live in Trinidad and Tobago so I can't fully appreciate the experience of being Black in the US and what is happening with the BLC. The race dynamics in my country are much more complex than the US. We have two racial groups, Indian and Black that exist as nearly equal majorities. But, because of colonialism we have institutions and norms which give preferential treatment to Whites. We're still in this position after 53 years as an independent state because we largely refuse to address race or talk about it.</p> <p>I very much agree with you when you say that race doesn't really exist. I think we use race as a proxy to talk about the other - people who differ from us in some way. We all have our tribes and favour our tribe above all others, be it our family, our community or our countrymen. But I find it hard to imagine having conversations about the downsides of tribalism, racism and inequality in my own country without starting with the concept of race.</p> <p>I have a rule of thumb for considering arguments. I think the extremes of any position are usually where the most erroneous arguments lie. Unfortunately, it's also where most people find themselves because accepting these extremes is the path of least resistance. Most people don't want to think about issues because it is hard and it is thankless work. Modern society only rewards independent thought if it leads to business value. There is no harm in accepting whatever the loudest person says, and even I fall prey to this at times.</p> <p>You talk about the RR, what do you think of it's sibling the Regressive Left?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487561</guid>
				<title>Re: There are a few points that I can argue with.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487561</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Honestly, I don't know&#8230; Reddit tends to nasty, for sure.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487483</guid>
				<title>Re: There are a few points that I can argue with.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487483</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 14:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Trial by media hardly looks like a legal process. But, if you insisted that it is a legal system, I could consider it as an informal form of custom law. Many communities are bad at practicing private laws, but we can learn to recognize communities with high quality laws.</p> <p>I recognize that a legal system of high quality has formalism. As Curtis Yarvin mentioned in one of his comments, formalism combined with precedence makes it easy to predict the outcomes of certain kinds of conflicts, and those kinds of conflicts could be defused more cheaply after setting a precedence. As the same precedences build up, it becomes easier to predict the outcomes. However, precedences could be applied more flexibly when customs change. That's how private laws based on precedence and custom evolve as customs change. The second factor that affects quality of legal service is competition. If many people had only a few communities, they would be effectively ruled under oligarchy in the long term.</p> <p>I'm slowly learning to recognize online communities with good rules. Many or most IRC channels are wastelands where standard of rudeness is set by trolls due to lack of peaceful and deliberate conflict resolution process as practiced by lambdaconf. In my experiences,<br /> IRC &lt; reddit &lt; lobste.rs ~= small slack channels &lt; small technical forums, but your experiences may differ. Where do you think we are likely to find high quality online communities?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487414</guid>
				<title>Re: There are a few points that I can argue with.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487414</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 11:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Yes, you're right that private laws are a first defense against bad actors&#8230; yet we are often terrible at doing this. Trial by media inevitably leads to hysteria where a few extremists can sway millions to hold views that would never survive careful analysis.</p> <p>I do think there are many places on the Internet where more careful debate happens, even if it's often combative.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487290</guid>
				<title>There are a few points that I can argue with.</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2487290</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 03:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>crocket</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>1794068</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <blockquote> <p>It is really a call for dissolution of the State, and the handing of power to self-selected individuals. A form of anarchy where the strongest rule over the weak. It is the psychopath's wet dream.</p> </blockquote> <p>I think it's half the truth. This gives an impression that the state law is good and anarchy is bad. Competition between private laws is a variant of anarchy often called polycentric law. Yet, they are often effective defense against bad actors.</p> <p>On <a href="http://degoes.net/articles/lambdaconf-inclusion">http://degoes.net/articles/lambdaconf-inclusion</a>, lambdaconf staff established a more sophisticated private legal system in response to SJW threats. Lambdaconf, from now on, judges people, based on conducts rather than ideologies. It is not just the state but also private legal systems that are threatened by people who try to legislate monopoly on rules. Also, governments already hold legal monopoly on people in their geographic regions. Personally, I don't care which entity(government, SJW, etc) is trying to legislate monopoly on laws as long as I'm screwed. I was tangibly screwed by government laws multiple times before. Monopoly in any market(legal, service, product, ..) hurts.</p> <p>I think private laws are important in our societies because it's private laws that are often the first line of defense and provide people with cheap, good, and fast defense against bad actors. Usually, I'd resort to government laws only after I run out of cheaper legal options(low-hanging fruit).</p> <blockquote> <p>I'm going to make an exception, and link to some of these tweets. Note the language and style used.</p> </blockquote> <p>I'm quite disappointed by David Nolen's responses on <a href="https://storify.com/adngyipa/lambdaconf-debate-in-tweets">https://storify.com/adngyipa/lambdaconf-debate-in-tweets</a>. I had general respect for his contribution to ClojureScript and its ecosystem.</p> <p>David Nolen accuses Curtis Yarvin(also known as mencius moldbug) for endorsing nazi racism on <a href="http://unqualified-reservations.blogspot.kr/2007/05/understanding-racial-idealism.html">http://unqualified-reservations.blogspot.kr/2007/05/understanding-racial-idealism.html</a>. I inspected the article, and the article actually seems to defend expelling jews from german and confiscating their properties. There are many other remarks that seem to defend nazi. Close inspection reveals that he endorses decentralism and thinks nazism, christianism, communism, and progressive idealism of USA and UK aren't great(<a href="http://unqualified-reservations.blogspot.kr/2007/05/idealism-is-not-great.html">http://unqualified-reservations.blogspot.kr/2007/05/idealism-is-not-great.html</a>). He's not a nazi racist, but he looks like one initially. That's how social media can falsely accuse people of horrible things. Such people as lambdaconf staff and court judges who make (private) legal decisions have to be indifferent, but random strangers are free to falsely accuse people of initial offensive impressions. The moral here is that relegating legal decisions to random strangers is totally crazy.</p> <p>I'll keep using Clojure and ClojureScript anyway because avoiding <strong>people whose views I don't agree with</strong> and <strong>their products</strong> is usually unproductive especially when the people I don't agree with are such important people as maintainers of softwares that I depend on everyday.</p> <blockquote> <p>Twitter let me promote my books, my writing, my talks. It was a way to keep in touch with people. And then there's that moment when you realize you're talking to an audience. Not friends, not colleagues. Rather, a group of mostly strangers.</p> </blockquote> <p>I very often feel that I talk to one-man audience when I try communicating via email or twitter with people I found on the internet. For example, I tried communicating with a book author, and he responded to my first email, but he somehow didn't like the second email from me, so he swiftly started ignoring my emails since then. Many people I tried to contact started ignoring me after my second or third email. Why would they mute others so quick? In my experiences, the vast majority of people are audiences who would mute you or me at the first signal of remarks they don't like. My life is painfully isolated. It feels that you are my only internet friend. Outside the internet, only my parents don't leave me just because I make a disagreeable remark or two. Isn't it too fast to mute others after only a very few disagreements? It seems too many people are avoiding discussion and disagreements. Maybe, I need to adjust to people's tenendecy to avoid even mild disagreements. In any case, I'm slowly accepting loneliness as an acceptable state of being.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479662</guid>
				<title>Re: Where will you be?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479662</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 15:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>iterOdos</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2174627</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Followers ≠ mindless sheep&#8230; Used &quot;followers&quot; because of twitter jargon that makes sense in this context.</p> <p>I'm not eating grass nor blindly swallowing whatever you through at us (and me in particular as one of your followers) as far as I know.</p> <p>&quot;set of people to argue with, openly and without emotion, about the difficult topics that face us.&quot;</p> <p>Is a good enough definition for me!</p> <p>Well, /u/pieterh, amen!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479651</guid>
				<title>Re: Where will you be?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479651</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I don't like having followers.</p> <p>What I seek are people to argue with, openly and without emotion, about the difficult topics that face us.</p> <p>I'm on Reddit (/u/pieterh) and will explore that for more controversial discussions.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479629</guid>
				<title>Where will you be?</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479629</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 14:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>iterOdos</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2174627</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>So, which (new ?) platform will you use?</p> <p>How will we know about it?<br /> I suspect at least one last twitter message to get us to that platform&#8230; unless you don't care for your followers?<br /> I bet you do!</p> <p>Cheers!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479616</guid>
				<title>An important loss</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:114/comments/show#post-2479616</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 14:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>1passant</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2664059</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi,<br /> As one of your many twitter followers, I wish I could beg you to reconsider.<br /> I do not agree 100% with everything you write, but this is precisely why I need your input.<br /> I'm sure other feel the same, and probably a lot who haven't had the opportunity to read you would feel the same if they had the chance to be exposed to your ideas.<br /> Anyway, I just registered to thank you for the way in which your writings (tweets and blog posts discovered via tweeter) changed me.<br /> I am very worried about the internet becoming a set of echo chambers, polarizing people into hatred. Your presence on Twitter was part of the solution and I will sorely miss it : when all the disguted leave, we are left with the disgusting (a saying I heard about politics).</p> <p>Thanks again for everything, I look forward to read more of you.</p> <p>Cheers !</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>